https://github.com/probinso

Personal Statement

I am currently a masters student at OHSU, studying computer science with a focus in signal processing and machine learning. In my several years of industry experience and prior degree, I developed strong interests in cryptography, reproducible research, statistical computing, and programming languages. I have adapted to, and adopted, a new or tool-set in nearly every challenge I have taken on. My interest in teaching and writing has also gained me strong communication skills.

Language Experience :

 \star Python Julia C, C++ ETEX Ada R Perl

Work Experience _

NASA Jet Propulsion Lab - Graduate Summer Research Intern June 2018 - Sept. 2018

Developing automatic Subject Matter Expert identification against failure report system Implemented principled text normalization, tokenization, and model evaluation strategies Open Source contributions to the gensim's natural language processing library

Languages Used: Python, gensim, pandas, jupyter, pyLDAvis

OHSU Fair Neuroimaging Lab - Research Support Engineer Oct. 2017 - June 2018

Contributed to workflows and analytics tools for studying Microbiome populations Supported research on developing brains, including ABCD, and several ADHD/ASD studies Developed processing pipeline and audit tools for reported data and FMRI images

Languages Used: Python, Bash, R, neo4j, ponyorm, stan

Contractor/Consultant

RGB Optics / C&W Energy USA

Nov. 2015 - Present

Provided live technology tutorials and consulting on optimization and image processing Light classification engine, custom photo image processing tools, and mathematical models Developed a cloud memoizing data pipeline for caching computationally expensive operations Provided hands on training to grow industry scientists in Python

ComScore June 2016 - Sept. 2016

Worked to support large, custom, memory mapped, data store for demographic analysis

PDXCodeGuild June 2016

Developed and taught introductory python course material for coding boot-camp

Melinae March 2016

Setup infrastructure in AWS to enable secure sustainable remote-first workflow Provided hands on training in Python and R to industry professionals

Languages Used : Python, R, AWS, PostgreSQL, Perl, C++

Galois Inc. - Research Engineer April 2014 - Dec 2015

Contributed to PPAML, Overseas Voting Foundation, Safeware, Robot Fast Track
Developed technologies and workflows to enable evaluator work for DARPA programs
Produced biannual quantitative and qualitative reports on for DARPA and language developers
Participated in programs sharing new technologies to research and industry professionals

Languages Used : Python, Scala, Figaro, Chimpy, Docker

EMC² Isilon Storage - Software Development Engineer Dec. 2012 - July 2013

Brought to schedule a lagging anchor release feature in approximately 5 months Designed and developed password manager to support Data At Rest Encryption Wrote unit tests using libcheck to attain > 80% code coverage

Languages Used : C, C++, Python, SQLite

Computer Science Dept. - Mentors Program Director Sept. 2009 - March 2012

Provided safe environment for training and instruction of students and mentors Wrote comprehensive quarterly reports, and tools for automatic report generation

Languages Used : Ada, C++, Scheme, R

Neato Projects

Whale vocals localization and analysis jupyter, matplotli Sensor Systems and Light Pollution Analysis aws, sklearn, skimage, Morphological Watershedding Algorithms numpy, Relevance Vector Machine	
Information Retrieval Cluster/Rank Demo Harness flask,	sklearn, Python
Gene Data Breast Cancer Drug Predictor	R, caret
N-Body Simulator	SIUnits, Julia
Probabilistic-Program Profiler and Evaluator Harness SLURM,	PonyORM, Python
Distributed Fully Homomorphic Encryption System	Hadoop, Python
Concurrent Elliptic Curve Cryptography Module	Sagemath, Erlang
Multilingual Analysis of Subordinating and Coordinating Conjunctions	R, Perl
AdaRailz Concurrent Model Train Control System	Ada
Fractal Art Generator & Image Manipulation Program	C#
Unix Shell	С
Liars Dice Game Server	С

Education _

Oregon Health Science University

CSLU

Computer Science MSc 2016 - present

Courses :

Digital Signal Processing
Problem Solving with Large Clusters
Image Processing
Machine Learning
Information Retrieval

Computing Ethics Statistical Methods Univariate Statistical Analysis Analysis of Sequences

Western Washington University

Computer Science

Computer Science BS, Mathematics Minor Sept. 2007 - June 2012